A Guide to the Molly Elliot Seawell Letters, 1888-1912
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Molly Elliot Seawell Letters, 1888-1912
The Library of Virginia
23830n
8 leaves and 10 pages
Molly Elliot Seawell
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 20 May 1952, from Aldine Book Company, Brooklyn, New York.
Biographical Information
Molly Elliot Seawell was born 12 October 1860 in Gloucester County, Virginia. While her formal education was sporadic, Seawell read the wide collection of works in her parents' library. After the death of her father, Seawell moved first to Norfolk, Virginia, then to Washington D.C. where she became a writer. Seawell supported her mother and her sister on the income she earned from her articles and books. Her works ranged from juvenile literature to political satire and she wrote 36 books and several articles. Some of her most popular works were naval adventures. Seawell's most successful novels were The History of the Lady Betty Stair, Throckmorton, A Virginia Cavalier, The House of Egremont, and The Whirl. Seawell was also an active anti-suffragette, writing The Ladies Battle to argue women weren't able to actively participate at the ballot box. Seawell conducted a popular salon for writers and artists in her Washington D.C. home located near Dupont Circle. She died 15 November 1916 in Washington D.C.
Scope and Content
Letters, 1888-1912, of Molly Elliot Seawell (1860-1916) of Gloucester County, Virginia, and Washington D.C., consisting of letters, 1888-1893[?], to her literary agent, Mr. Stoddard, concerning The Berkeleys and Their Neighbors and discussing her attempts to sell The History of the Lady Betty Stair; letters, 1900, regarding writing The House of Egremont, its serial rights, and a portion of a typescript of the book; letter, 4 April 1902, concerning the publication of a short-story; letter, 22 December 1912, concerning the publication of "The Show Girl;" and biographical sketches of Molly Elliot Seawell.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Molly Elliot Seawell Letter, 12 February 1891 (LVA accession 32006).
Contents List
- Letter, 27 December 1888, to her literary agent, Mr. Stoddard, concerning The Berkeleys and Their Neighbors.
- Letter, 1 February 1893[?], to Mr. Stoddard discussing her attempts to sell The History of the Lady Betty Stair.
- Letter, 11 January 1900, to an unnamed recipient regarding writing The House of Egremont and its serial rights.
- Letter, 3 March 1900, to an unnamed recipient concerning The House of Egremont, its serial rights, and a missing copy of a portion of the book.
- Letter, 13 March 1900, to an unnamed recipient regarding the serial rights to The House of Egremont.
- Letter, 7 April 1900, to an unnamed recipient again concerning the serial rights to The House of Egremont.
- Letter, 16 April 1900, to an unnamed recipient again regarding the serial rights to The House of Egremont.
- Letter, 20 April 1900, to Mr. Valentine concerning a typescript copy of a portion of The House of Egremont.
- Letter, 4 April 1902, to an unnamed recipient concerning the publication of a short-story.
- Letter, 22 December 1912, to an unnamed recipient concerning the publication of "The Show Girl."
- Biographical sketches of Molly Elliot Seawell.